Hey.
哟
You are new here?
你们新来的
Hello, senior.
学长好
The two campuses of the Western University of Science and Technology
我们是西科大校区
merged
两校合并
and our classes were
然后我们的课
all arranged in the east side
都安排在东区这边
so we were
所以就被
arranged to live here.
安排到这边来住了
Fine.
行
This dormitory has exactly
刚好 这个寝室
three empty beds.
空三张床
We should take care of each other from now on.
以后就相互照顾了啊
Hello.
你好
Is this room 227?
这是二二七房间吗
Do you live here too?
你也住这儿吗
Yeah.
对啊
Where do I live then?
那我住哪儿
Sa
小撒
Yeah.
嗯
You don't have to be nervous.
你不用紧张
I know these kids
这帮孩子
too well.
我太了解了
When they came to see me for the first time
他们头一次来看我
they looked
看上去
so calm
一个个风轻云淡
as if nothing had happened.
跟没事一样
I knew in my heart
我心里很明白
they were not convinced
他们心里是
that they had lost.
不服气他们输了
I'll do it.
我来 我来 我来
Thank you.
谢谢
Coach
教练
It's my turn.
该我了
OK, hurry up.
好好 你快点
Come on.
快走
Checkmate.
将军
This doesn't count. My piece hasn't fallen yet.
不算啊 我子没落呢
This doesn't count.
这不算
Look
你看啊
there's room for maneuver
凡事啊
in everything.
都有回旋的余地
It's the same
这帮孩子
with these kids.
打交道也是一样
They have this enthusiasm in their hearts
他们心里这股劲顶着
but
但是
you can't deny
你不能否认
the fact that
他们喜欢
they like debating.
辩论这个事实
Yeah.
嗯
Right.
是
But from team one to the team two
但是从一队变成二队
I can imagine
我都能想象到
the looks on their faces.
他们那张脸
You have to believe in yourself
你要相信自己
and more importantly, in your students.
更要相信你的学生
Right?
啊
Hum.
嗯
Checkmate.
将军
It's a surprise.
这是出其不意啊
Did you hear that?
听说了吗
This afternoon
今天下午
the nursing department will take free blood pressure tests
护理系在食堂门口
in front of the dining hall.
免费测血压
Oh.
哦
Nan Bei
南北
Don't say I'm not a true friend.
可别说哥们不够意思啊
It's hard to get a ticket
每次检查活动
for each test.
是一票难求
This time one of my friends
这次我一姐妹
reserved a place for me.
给我留了位子
I have no time.
没空
My blood pressure is steady, a straight line.
我血压平稳 一条直线
Come on.
走啊
How about we go out and exercise?
要不我们出去排排汗
Rest breeds rust.
生命在于运动
Basketball, football, and table tennis...
篮球 足球 乒乓球
No. Tennis.
不 网球
Hello.
你们好啊
You are here
你这是
to sell the cart?
推销小推车来了
Such a coincidence.
这么巧
My
我
dormitory is occupied by freshmen
宿舍被西科大
of the Western University of Science and Technology.
大一给占了
The school has arranged for me
学校安排我从今儿起
to live with you guys from now on.
就跟你们几个住了
Do you know each other?
你们认识啊
Ma Nan
马楠
A buddy in the fifth year of college.
大五的一哥们
The fifth year...
大五
It's all fate.
都是缘分
Just welcome me casually.
不用太隆重
No need to be too grand.
随便欢迎欢迎我就行
Let's go and play tennis.
走了 打网球去吧
let's go.
走啊
Come on. Rest breeds rust.
走嘛 生命在于运动
Come on.
快快快
Fine.
哎
First look at my movements.
首先看我的动作
Pay attention to the actions.
注意动作要领
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
Everyone practices
两两为一组
in groups of two.
大家练习一下
Nan Bei
南北
I don't know
我有句话
whether to tell you or not.
不知当不当讲
Please.
请讲
I'm almost burned.
我快熟了
Well.
不是
The three of us don't know how to play tennis
我们仨也不会打网球
so what are we doing here?
我们在这儿干嘛呢
Why don't we
咱们去打会儿
play basketball for a while?
篮球不香吗
Let's fight with them.
跟他们厮杀一会儿
So you are
所以说你这个人
destined to be lonely forever.
就是注定孤独终生
A group of sweaty muscular men
篮球场一群
on the basketball court.
汗流浃背肌肉棒子
How can there be
哪有这里一片
a beautiful landscape like this?
美丽的风景线
Come on, posture ready.
来 姿势准备
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
Good. Danger cleared.
好 危险解除
It's fine.
还行
I'm not doing this.
我不打了 你们打吧
I'm going to play basketball.
我打篮球去
I'm...
我真
Hey.
嘿
What?
干嘛
What are you doing?
干啥呢
Nothing.
没事
Okay, class
好 同学们
that's all for today.
今天的课就上到这儿
Lin
小林
Do you have something
你是不是有什么事情
to tell your classmates?
要跟同学们说呀
I have a notice
我通知一下事情啊
to all sophomore students.
大二同学都注意一下
Next Friday at 2:30 p.m.
下礼拜五下午两点半
there will be the physical test for men 1,000 meters
体测 男生一千米
women 800 meters.
女生 八百米
Don't forget and please be on time.
都准点到 别忘了
Okay, class's over.
好 下课
Let's go out to eat.
吃东西 出去吃饭
Well.
那个
I'm not going. I don't have the appetite.
我不吃 我没胃口
I'm going back to the dormitory.
我先回寝室了啊
Ah?
啊
Dude
哥们儿
I'm going to the tennis court
我打算去网球场
to run
跑两圈
and practice.
练一练
Let's go together.
一块去呗
We have a football field.
咱们有足球场
Why you have to go to the tennis court?
你非要去网球场跑
Are you doing it for that girl?
你是不是为了那姑娘
Let's go.
走
Have you figured it out?
想好了吗
Do you want to go to team two?
要不要去二队呀
No.
不去
Don't want to be their backup.
给他们当备胎打下手
If Yin Nan asked me
你说殷楠让我给她
to copy an argument for her,
复印个论点
would I take two copies
我是给她抽掉两张
or smear it for her?
还是给她印糊了呀
If I were you
要是我呀
I'd just smash it.
直接给她搅碎了
Did you really get the answer?
你真想好了
Yeah.
嗯
When I first joined the school team
我大一刚进
in my freshman year
校队的时候吧
I thought
觉着自己
I was really good at debating.
辩论打得是真不错
However, through this competition
但是通过这次比赛呢
I finally understood one thing.
我总算明白了一件事
What's that?
什么呀
People
人哪
should not force themselves.
就不应该勉强自己
Yin Nan's talent
人殷楠天赋
is higher than me
就是比我高
and her debate is better than me.
辩论打得就是比我好
Why do I have to
我干嘛没事
look for trouble?
非得往枪口上撞呢
Right?
对不对
I just can't beat her now
我现在就是打不过她
but sooner or later
不过早晚有一天
there will be someone
会有一个辩论打得
who is better than her
比她还好的人
and teach her a lesson
在辩论场上
in the debate.
狠狠地教训她
Don't be so modest.
你别这么谦虚
I think
我觉得呀
you are better than her
你身上有很多点
in many points.
都比她强
For example?
比如呢
For example...
比 比如
For example, you are her junior.
比如你是她学妹
Your theory is younger than hers.
你理论上就比她年轻
But to be honest
但我说真的啊
I really
我对辩论这事
have no confidence
真的是
in debate anymore.
一点信心都没有了
Even if I were in team two
就算进了二队
I honestly
我说实话
don't have much confidence in
也没什么信心
playing well in the points race.
打好积分赛
That's good.
那正好
I'm not going anyway.
反正我也不去
If you have
到时候你要有什么
any new ideas,
新的方向啊
remember to tell me.
记得叫上我
You don't have to think about me.
你不用考虑我
Just go if you want.
你去你的
We made a deal
我们都说好了
to win the championship together.
一起拿冠军的
That's our deal.
那是咱俩说好了
Who want to
谁跟他们一块
win the championship with them?
拿冠军啊
Besides
再说了
I didn't want to join them.
我本来也不想去
Why not?
为什么呀
I'm a dignified man.
我堂堂八尺男儿汉
It would be humiliated for me
我给他刘彦泽打下手
to act as an assistant of Liu Yanze.
拉不下来这脸
Shabby-genteel.
死要面子
Then let's make a deal that
那咱俩说好了
no one will go.
谁也不去
Deal.
一言为定
Hello, check please.
你好 买单
Is your new hobby photography
你这新爱好是摄影
or sneak shots?
还是偷拍啊
What?
干嘛呀
Give it to me.
给我
A bad-looking shot is called a sneak shot
拍得不好看叫偷拍
and a good-looking one is called a snapshot.
拍得好看叫抓拍
Here. Let me have a look.
来来 我看看 我看看
Oh.
哦
It has kind of
还挺有
postmodernist style.
后现代主义的风格的
German artist
德国艺术家
Richter once said
纪希里特说过
photo
照片
is the perfect painting.
就是最完美的绘画
Look
你看 这张照片
the core of this photo
它的思想内核
is idealism
一看就是唯心
and metaphysics.
和形而上
Look.
看看人家
You do understand.
还是你懂行
After seeing Xiaoyu
见过小鱼之后
things get different.
确实不一样了啊
You completely come alive.
彻底活过来了
It's more useful
比我们哥几个
than us.
管用多了
Right, Mengyuan?
是不是梦圆
The mountains have trees and trees have branches.
山有木兮木有枝
The mountains have trees.
山有木兮
Mengyuan
梦圆
What are you doing?
你干嘛呢你
What are you talking about?
说啥呢你 说人话
You're in love.
你思春了这是
What's going on? Be honest.
什么情况 老实交代
Say something!
说话呀
Don't say anything, right?
不说话是吧
Fine.
行
Come on.
来吧
Once upon a time there was a mountain.
从前有座山呀
There was a temple in the mountain.
山里有座庙啊
There was an old monk in the temple
庙里有个老和尚
who kept ringing the bell every day.
每天老敲钟啊
Wait, wait, wait.
等等 等等 等等
I met true love.
遇见真爱了
Gao Jingwen
高静雯
Gao Jingwen, right?
高静雯啊
The one who plays tennis, right?
打网球那个是吧
Yeah.
啊
Love at first sight, right?
一见钟情是吧
That's pretty much it.
差不多得了啊
I'll help you check her out.
哥们给你查户口去
Yeah.
嗯
What's going on?
怎么了
Are you sick?
生病了
No.
没有
The physical test is coming.
这不是要体测了吗
I have 800-meter-panic.
八百米恐慌
Qing, don't be afraid.
小晴 你不要怕
By the time
到时候
we will all be with you.
我们都会陪着你的
Alas.
哎
Since junior high school
自从初中开始
I ran off half a life
考八百米
for 800 meters test
我每次跑掉
each time
半条命不说
but never passed.
还从来没有及格过
In the middle school examination,
中考的时候
if I had not crawled through the line
要不是我爬着过线
and earned some sympathy,
挣了点同情分
I could not even go to senior high school.
我连高中都上不了
Senior high school also has sports points.
高 高中也有体育分
Because I was so scared
我因为太害怕了
I had nightmares every day and suffered hair loss.
每天做噩梦 掉头发
Finally, the hospital
最后医院
gave me a mental certificate.
给我开了精神证明
It will not be so strict in the university.
大学不会那么严的
The teachers are very nice.
老师们都很好
I didn't even have the courage
我连走到跑道的
to walk to the runway.
勇气都没有
I got an idea.
有办法了
What? Where are you going?
干嘛 你要去哪儿
I drop out of school
我 我退学
and repeat my senior high.
然后我再复读一年
Next year, I will be admitted
明年再考一个
to a university that does not need to
不需要
run 800 meters.
跑八百米的大学
Well.
那个
The 800-meter test is a hard target for universities.
八百米是大学硬指标
Every university has it.
每个大学都有
The 800-meter test has already begun?
已经开始考八百米了
Not yet.
那倒还没有
See how scared you are.
瞧把你给吓的
But since you
不过你既然不做
don't do planning,
规划的话
we can only do it for you.
姐妹们只能代劳了
First, running training.
第一项 跑步训练
Breakfast is ready
早餐都已经买好了
get up.
赶快起来吧
No. No way.
不行 不可能
I'm not going.
我不去
I'll fall there
我不出二百米
within 200 meters.
我就倒那儿了
Really, believe me.
真的 你们相信我
Leave me alone.
别管我了
Then we'll have to do it.
那姐妹们可就动手了
Come on.
上
Just leave me alone.
你们就放过我吧
Try it, just in case it works.
试试吧 万一能行呢
I've tried it all my life.
我都试一辈子了
If it could work, it would have worked long ago.
能成早就成了
Sis, please.
大姐 拜托你了
For the sake of
你就看在我们
we accompany you
几个大热天
to run
还陪你来
in such a hot day,
跑步的份儿上
try again.
再试一次
Yeah.
嗯
I'm not sure
我肯定
if I could make it.
不一定能成功啊
Don't get your hopes up.
你们别抱太大希望
I may be stuck
我可能二百米就
on 200 meters.
就卡了
Are you ready for this?
准备好了吗
Ready?
预备
Go.
跑
Oops.
哎呀
Qing
小晴
Are you okay?
你没事吧
I forgot to tell you just now.
刚才忘了告诉你们
Every time I ran 800 meters
我每次跑八百米
I would be too nervous
都会因为太紧张
and fall in a few steps.
没跑几步就摔了
Why are you so scared?
你怎么会这么害怕呢
In the second year of senior high
高二那会儿
there was a time when our class
有一次我们班
and the class next door
和隔壁班
ran the 800 meters together.
一块上八百米
There was a boy in the next class
当时隔壁班
who wanted to help me.
有个男生想帮助我
He knew I couldn't run fast
他知道我跑不快
so he ran on my track
就跑到我这条跑道上
and led me to run.
带着我跑
As a result, I was nervous and fell.
结果我一紧张就摔了
He couldn't stop
他没刹住闸
and stepped right over me.
直接从我身上踩过去了
Ah?
啊
Anyway
反正这个事
I have tried quite a few times for this.
我也努力过挺多次了
I know that I really can't do it.
我自己知道我是真不行
So it's better to give up.
所以还是放弃吧
No.
不行
There is still a long time
离八百米考试
before the 800 meters test.
还有好久呢
Let's think about it.
再想想办法
You should find something else
你们还是找点别的
to waste time.
浪费时间的事做吧
Can you understand how I feel?
我的感受你们能懂吗
I understand.
我懂
Just like me in the debate.
就跟我打辩论似的呗
No matter how motivated I am or how hard I try
不管我多上进 多努力
I just can't win against Yin Nan.
我就是赢不了殷楠
In the past, I would take it too hard.
以前还会想不开
Now I have got over it.
我现在想开了
If you can't do it, just accept it.
做不到就是做不到
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
没什么可丢脸的
How is it?
怎么样 怎么样
Stop.
停
You always pinch me when you get excited.
你一激动容易捏疼我
Step back.
往后退
Sit down.
坐
Mengyuan
梦圆
I really envy you
我真羡慕你有
for having such a good buddy like me.
我这么好的哥们
I've made all the inquiries for you.
我都帮你打听好了
Goddess Gao Jingwen,
女神高静雯
sophomore at the art department,
大二艺术系
who is gentle and quiet, and loves painting and calligraphy.
温婉恬静 爱好书画
She lives in the building
家住马路后
opposite the second alley.
第二胡同对面大厦
She's definitely a beauty from a decent family.
妥妥白富美
Single.
单身
Sit down.
坐
Then the man next door in 201
那隔壁二零一那男的
expressed love to her
告白就是她呀
and scattered flowers all over the place.
还把花撒一地
It's normal.
倒也正常
Since Gao Jingwen started college
人家女神上大学以来
she has rejected someone
每隔几天
every few days.
都会拒绝一个人
I have asked around for you.
我都帮你打听好了
Gao Jingwen goes to the school gym
人家女神每天放学
every day after school.
都会去学校健身房
Every Tuesday and Thursday
每周二 周四
she usually goes to play tennis.
一般都会去打网球
She broke up two years ago.
人家分手两年了
Her ex-boyfriend
前男友是
was the top student of college entrance exam in their city.
他们市高考状元
Later he was admitted to Peking University
后来去北大
so they broke up.
两个人就分了
Let's forget about it.
要不还是算了吧
Hey.
哎
You can't.
不能算
Didn't you have to marry her before?
之前不还非人不娶吗
Well.
不是
She is not a goddess.
这哪儿是女神呀
She is obviously a fairy.
这分明是仙女
I suck.
我太挫了
Obviously
这明摆着
I won't be able to make it
我肯定是成不了
and I'll lose face when the time comes.
到时候还丢面子
Stand up.
站起来
Mengyuan
梦圆
What?
干嘛
If you are a man, show some confidence.
是男人就拿出点自信来
You have many advantages.
你有很多优点
For example?
比如呢
Yuan
小圆仔
Go ahead.
去啊
Don't dare to.
不敢
You don't dare. You...
你不敢 你
That's your true love.
那不真爱吗 你不敢
So I should be cautious.
所以要谨慎啊
If you like her, go ahead.
喜欢你就去
What are you hesitating for?
纠结什么呢你
Why are you working so hard
天天健身房
in the gym every day?
这么努力为了啥
Strengthen my body.
强健体魄
If you're still stalling, I'll kick you.
你再磨磨唧唧拍死你我
Don't suppress your nature.
你别压抑自己天性
If you like her, just go.
喜欢你就得去
Okay, I'll go.
好 我去
Go.
去
What am I going to do?
我去干什么呀
You still need to rely on me at this critical time.
这关键时候还得靠我
Here.
来吧
Take it and give her.
拿着 送水去
Go for it.
加油
What's the matter?
你有事吗
I can't unscrew this bottle of water.
这瓶水我拧不开
Can you help me?
你能帮我拧一下吗
He...
他 他 他
Thank you.
谢谢
Hell.
我去
You pissed me off.
气死我了
You are a seven-foot man.
你堂堂七尺大老爷们
You let a girl to unscrew the bottle cap.
你让一女孩给你拧瓶盖
What are you thinking of?
你怎么想的你
Don't give up.
寝室长 你不要放弃
Go.
走
Don't give up on me.
别放弃我呀
Get a towel.
拿下毛巾
Go and wipe her sweat.
来 给她擦汗去
Show her your tender man side.
展示你柔情男人的一面
You, hurry up.
你 你快去呀
What's wrong?
你又怎么了
Here.
给
Towel.
毛巾
Say it.
快说 说
Ten yuan for each.
十块钱一条
Do you want one?
要吗
I...
我
No, thanks.
不用了 谢谢
Never mind.
不要算了
Why is this man
这个男的怎么
a bit naive?
有点憨憨的
Yeah.
还行吧
I think he's foolish
觉得他傻不啦叽
and kind of funny.
还挺好玩
Come here.
来来来
You can't even do such a little thing.
这么点事都干不好
It's just to flirt with girls.
不就是撩妹吗
If I were you
我要是我
I'd take her down in a minute.
分分钟给她拿下
Can you do it?
行不行啊你
Oh
哎哟
I didn't see it before.
看不出来啊
You are quite capable.
挺有本事的
No.
不是
Do you know what's going on?
你知道那是什么情况吗
That is a lifelong business for him.
那是人家终身大事
You have been sighing all day.
这都叹一天气了
Life is bottlenecked again?
人生又遇到瓶颈了
Stuck before the bottleneck is reached.
还没遇到瓶颈就卡住了
How can I
到底怎么样才能
talk to her?
跟女神搭上话呀
Just accost her directly.
直接搭讪呀
Fast, accurate, and tough.
快 准 狠
When Mengyuan finds the topic
等梦圆找到话题
she will be full of children and grandchildren.
人家都子孙满堂了
It doesn't matter. Let's give her a gift.
没关系 咱送礼
If she doesn't accept the gift
送了呢 人要不收
at least you can talk to her.
咱也算说上话了
If she takes it
她要收了呢
that is the token of love.
这就是定情信物
Such a good deal!
多赚呀
What should I give her then?
那 那送什么呀
USB flash drive.
优盘哪
You can also engrave on it.
还能刻字
Why it sounds
我怎么听着
so obscene?
就那么猥琐呢
Hey.
哎哎哎 哎
That's it.
就这个
Look, it makes girls
你看 把人女孩都
crying.
都给整哭了
Can it work?
这能行吗
Oh my god, buy it!
我的天哪 买它
Are you retarded?
你有病吧
I told you to buy roses.
不是 我让你买玫瑰花
Did I ask you to buy Lotus?
我让你买莲花了吗
You...
你这
Can you two be serious?
你们俩能不能认真点
Huh?
啊
I'm still counting on you two
我还指望你们俩
to help me get her heart.
帮我脱单呢
Of course.
脱 脱 脱 脱单
Don't be sad.
别伤心
Don't be discouraged. Be confident.
别灰心 有点自信
For girl's gift
送女孩子嘛
cosmetics is the eternal first choice.
化妆品才是永恒的首选
Good boy.
乖啊
This one.
这个
This is the one.
就这个
Oh my god, buy it!
我的天哪 买它
My son.
儿子
It's been more than a week
距你失踪
since you disappeared.
已经一周有余了
Where are you now?
你现在在哪里啊
How are you doing?
过得好不好
Mom missed you so much.
妈妈好想你
Where are you going?
你干什么去
Tao Hao said
陶好姐说了
re-examination is not possible.
复考是不行的
I've already had a plan.
我规划好了
The head of the department is going to Guangzhou
系主任他要去广州
for a seminar.
参加研讨会
I've applied to be his assistant.
我申请了做他的助手
By the time there will be typhoon in Guangzhou.
到时候广州台风天气
The flight will be canceled.
飞机肯定停飞呀
If we take the high-speed train, we will be back at night
高铁回来就晚上了
and perfectly miss the physical test.
完美错过体测
Start to risk your life.
开始豁命了你这是
What's wrong with you again?
你又怎么了
The organizers said that
主办方说了
the seminar was postponed
考虑到台风天气
in consideration of the safety of travel
大家出行安全
in typhoon weather.
把研讨会延后了
You can think of a life-threatening way.
你都想到豁命的方法
It's no big deal to take the test.
大不了考一考
I think for people like you
我觉得你的人设
maybe it will work.
没准能行呢
Do not persuade Qing.
你也别劝人家小晴了
If she can't run 800 meters
跑不了八百米
she just can't.
就是跑不了八百米嘛
Why do you have to
干嘛非得
let her fail again?
让她再失败一次
Right?
对吧
I'm with you.
我支持你
Xiaoyu
小鱼
I had a problem with my computer.
我电脑出了点问题
Lend me yours for a while.
你的借我用一下
I need to send an email soon.
我得赶紧发个邮件
Okay, the password is my birthday.
好 密码是我生日
I'm going out for a while.
正好我出去一下
I have an appointment with Nan Bei.
约了南北
Have fun.
玩得开心
Hey, we're closing.
同学 要关门了
Come tomorrow.
明天再来吧
Okay, right away.
好 马上
Let's go then.
那走吧
Give me a second, Nan Bei.
稍等我一下 南北
I'll write down this point.
我把这个点稍微记一下
It's particularly good.
这个点特别好
The next debate we will definitely...
咱们下次辩论肯定
Let's go.
走吧
Get a cup of milk tea.
买杯奶茶去
No.
不要
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了
The 800-meter physical test is coming next week.
下周八百米体测
I'm so annoyed.
烦得慌
You are so strong, what are you afraid of?
你那么强壮你怕什么呀
Overthinking.
多虑了
Is that me?
是我吗
It's Qing.
是小晴
What's wrong with her?
她怎么了
She has a phobia of 800 meters.
她八百米恐惧症
In order to escape the physical test
为了逃体测
she's going to go back to senior high school.
都要复读了
Isn't the physical test easy?
考个体测还不简单啊
You've got an idea?
你又有办法了
Do you feel that
你觉不觉得
something is calling me?
有什么在呼唤我
Yes?
有吗
Yes, I guess.
有吧
Ahh?
啊
Wait.
不是
Yes or not?
有没有啊
We are hiding like this.
咱们就这么缩着
What is the point of it?
有什么意义呀
Hey.
哎哟
Tianchong
天重同学
Nan Bei
南北
Where are you going? The gym?
干嘛去 你健身去
What a coincidence.
真巧
Bye-Bye.
拜拜
Just the right size.
大小正合适
Tony
托尼
From now on
以后这里
this will be your home.
可就是你的家了
It's really little Xiaoyu.
果然是小小鱼
That's my son.
那是我儿子
Mu Xiaoyu
牧小鱼
What are you talking about?
你胡说什么呢
This is my Tony.
这是我的托尼
Don't be afraid, senior.
别怕 学姐
I'm here.
这里有我
Mu Xiaoyu
牧小鱼
I'm warning you to stop this nonsense.
我警告你别胡闹
You haven't forgotten that
你没忘了我
I'm an orange belt in karate, have you?
是空手道橙带吧
You want to practice?
想练练是吧
Fine.
可以呀
Good evening.
二位 晚上好啊
The visibility tonight
今天晚上这能见度
for the stars...
星星没
There's no star.
没有星星
You tell me
你给我说
why you have it?
它为什么在你那儿
A meeting of destiny.
命运的相遇
Ugh.
呸
You have no idea
你根本不知道
how painful it is.
它有多痛苦
I don't know what you are talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
You don't know how happy Tony is
托尼跟我在一起
to be with me.
不知道有多幸福
You don't understand it at all.
你根本不了解它
What's going on here?
怎么了这是
Looks like they're
好像是在抢
vying for a guy named Tony.
一个叫托尼的人
Well...
那个 那个
If you don't want to
假如二位
be in the hot searches tomorrow
明天不想上热搜的话
turn down the volume a little bit.
把音量稍微调小
Okay?
一点好不好
You give it back to me.
你把它还给我
Boring.
无聊
Yin Nan, come back.
殷楠 你给我回来
Calm down, calm down.
冷静 冷静
You give it back to me.
你把它还给我
Calm down, outwit her.
冷静 智取 智取 智取得
Nan Bei, you are most unqualified
南北 你最没有资格
to say such things to me.
跟我说这样的话了
If it weren't for you
要不是因为你的话
Tony and I wouldn't be separated at all.
我跟托尼根本不会分开
Let's get out of here.
换个地说 换个地说
Wonderful.
精彩了
The girl cheated first.
居然是女方先劈腿
Life is like a drama.
人生如戏呀
Not anyone else
让谁捡着不好
but Yin Nan picked it up.
让殷楠捡着了
Fine.
好
Everything has its pros and cons.
凡事都有正反面
You know it's alive now
你现在知道它还活着
isn't it a big blessing?
这不一大幸事吗
Can you stop talking?
你能别说话了吗
Does Yin Nan know my son?
殷楠了解我儿子吗
She knows nothing.
她一无所知
What is little Xiaoyu's
小小鱼最喜欢吃的
favorite food?
是什么
It's cucumber strips.
是黄瓜条
What it loves to do?
它最爱做的是什么
It's to relax the muscles and bones
是没事在寝室里面
in the dormitory.
舒活舒活筋骨
It likes to listen to
它最喜欢听的是
Katy Perry's songs the most.
凯蒂佩里的歌
Does Yin Nan know about these?
这些殷楠知道吗
She doesn't know.
她不知道
My son must
我儿子现在
don't want to live now.
一定生不如死
As its mother
我这个当妈的
now I'm going to save it.
现在就要去救它
OK. I wish you an early reunion
好好好 祝你早日
with your little Xiaoyu.
早日和你小小鱼团聚
But do you have a plan?
但是 你有计划吗
Nan Bei, come here.
南北 你过来一下
There's no one else here.
这儿没别人啊
Come here.
过来一下
What?
说
Don't make it as if
你别搞得跟
it's nothing to do with you.
没你事儿似的
You lost little Xiaoyu.
小小鱼是你弄丢的
You give it back.
你还给我
It hurts.
疼 掉了要
Generally this situation
一般这种情况呢
is a psychological effect.
就是心理作用
Let me diagnose you.
让我来给你诊断一下
Hold your breath.
屏住呼吸
Inhale.
大口吸气
Um...
嗯
Your bones are unusual.
看你骨骼清奇
You should be a great athlete.
应该是个运动健将
What era is it?
什么年代了
It's 0202.
零二零二年了
You diagnose psychological problems
你给人看心理问题
through pulse?
搭脉呀
Right.
就是
We are here
我们今天是
to solve problems today.
来解决问题的
No time to fool around with you.
没工夫在这跟你瞎扯
You can't avoid it.
这事是不能逃避的
We have to find a way to solve it.
我们得想办法解决它
Or I'd rather take a look at
要不我还是看看
that seminar.
那个研讨会
No, no, no.
别别别
One more chance.
再给一次机会
A good student
一个八百米呀
is driven to revolt
就把一个好学生
by an eight-hundred-meter.
逼上梁山
Can there be another way?
还能不能有别的办法呀
At the moment
目前来看
there is no other way but to face it.
除了硬上没有别的办法
It doesn't work as expected.
果然不行啊
Be detected.
被识破了啊
What is as expected?
什么叫果然
Let me tell you
我跟你说
you'd better be smart
营救我儿子的计划
for the plan to rescue my son.
你最好做聪明点
Otherwise, you'll be punished for all your crimes
要不然数罪并罚
and you'll spend the rest of your life
下辈子等着在
in a wheelchair.
轮椅上过吧你
Relax.
放心
I've got it all planned out.
我都计划好了
First, you need to find a time
首先 你就要找一个
when Yin Nan is not in the dormitory.
殷楠不在宿舍的时间
I will attract the attention
由我吸引
of the dorm keeper.
宿管阿姨的存在
You successfully
你成功进入到
enter the senior dormitory.
高年级宿舍
When you get little Xiaoyu
你拿到小小鱼之后
don't rush out
不要着急出来
because you will be captured by the camera.
因为会被摄像头拍到
You need to disguise.
你需要乔装
Tie little Xiaoyu with a rope
用绳子 绑住小小鱼
and bring it down from the window.
从窗户运下来
I'll be responsible for the reception from below.
我在下面负责接应
When we get little Xiaoyu
拿到小小鱼之后
meet here.
在这里会合
Mission accomplished.
大功告成
Isn't it a perfect plan?
是不是很完美的计划
Not too bad.
凑合
Move.
行动
Auntie
阿姨
Do you know
你知道我第一次
what gift I gave my mom the first time
送我妈生日
for her birthday?
什么生日礼物吗
I...
我主要是我
gave her a baseball.
送了一个棒球
You know?
你知道吗
Just a bat
不是 就一棒
it was hit there.
就 就 打到那儿去了
Hello.
您好
Hey.
喂
Yin Nan's dormitory door
殷楠的宿舍这个门
was locked.
反锁了呀
Ah.
啊
She might have locked it.
她可能会反锁的
But it doesn't matter.
不过没关系
This is a little problem
这都是可以解决的
and can be solved.
小问题
Now you find a hairpin.
你现在找一根发卡
Wait.
等会儿啊
I'll teach you to unlock on the phone.
我现在电话教你解锁
Then?
然后呢
First break the hairpin open
首先把卡子掰开
and put it into the lock hole.
放进锁孔里边
You unlock the electronic lock with a hairpin?
你家用发卡开电子锁
What do you think this year is, 1902?
你以为这一九零二年哪
Electronic lock?
电子锁啊
Yeah.
对呀
Password
密码的话
try
你试试
one one one one.
一一一一
Operation failed.
操作失败
It's not right.
不对呀
One one one two.
一一一二
Operation failed.
操作失败
It doesn't work.
不行啊
I get it.
有了
One one one three.
一一一三
Idiot Nan Bei. I would have died here
死南北 我等试出来
when I try it out.
我老死在这儿
Eagle homing.
雄鹰归巢
Repeat, eagle homing.
重复 雄鹰归巢
Hello.
您好
Why are you running again?
你怎么又跑步呢
I was thinking
我在想
that if I run myself to prostration
如果我把自己跑虚脱了
and my brain goes blank,
大脑空白了
I will
是不是这样
stop thinking about Jingwen all the time?
就不会老想着静雯了
Alas.
哎
Here it is.
来了
Waiting for your reply in two days.
两天后等大家的答复哟
Are you really not going?
你真的不去吗
No.
不去
I definitely won't go.
说不去就不去
Do you want to order or not?
你点 还是不点
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Then two cups of Quan Jiafu.
那就两杯全家福
Grande, no ice and no sugar.
大杯去冰 无糖
OK.
好
Tao Hao
陶好
Senior
学长
Are you okay? Does it hurt?
没事吧 疼吗
No.
不疼
Then why are you covering your chest?
那你捂着胸口干什么呀
Stress response triggered by the hit
撞击引发的应激性反应
results in rapid blood backflowing.
导致血液急速回收
It may cause sudden death.
可能会引发猝死
You have this disease?
你有这个病啊
Not really.
那倒没有
Oh.
哦
It's about team two, isn't it?
二队的事是吧
Nan Bei said to me
南北跟我说过
how to say it
怎么说呢
a living dog is better than a dead lion, right?
好死不如赖活着 对吧
Tao Hao
陶好学姐
The first half-yearly statement of club property
办公室李老师桌上
is on Mr. Li's desk in the office.
上半年社团财物报表
Could you please send it to Building One?
能麻烦送到一号楼吗
Shui
水哥
Give me a latte, please.
你给我来一杯拿铁
Okay, scan the code yourself.
好 自己扫码
Yeah.
哦
Why are the pockets so deep?
怎么口袋这么深了
Senior, let me pay it.
学长 我来吧
That's not right. I'll do it.
那多不好意思 我来吧
On me.
我来吧
Thank you.
谢谢啊
So do you want to go to team two?
那你自己想去二队吗
If they want to go, I want to go.
他们想去我就想去
Oh.
哦
Thank you.
谢谢
Why is yours so fast?
你的怎么这么快呀
I know what I want
我知道自己想要什么
of course it's fast.
当然快
If you want everything
那如果什么都想要
of course it will be slow.
当然慢咯
Young girl
小样
where are you going?
去哪儿啊
Don't look at me.
你别看我
I am on the same side with them.
我跟她们是一边的
Take her back.
带走
No, no, no.
别别别
No, I'm not running away.
不是 我不是要逃跑
I'm going to Guangzhou.
我是要去那个
That seminar is open again.
广州那研讨会它又开了
So I have to...
所以我得
I've already heard from Mr. Li.
我已经听李主任说过了
You have long been removed from the list.
你呀 早就被除名了
You guys just let me go.
你们放过我吧
I really don't want to run 800 meters.
我真不想跑八百米
Let's go back and talk about it.
有什么事咱回去再说
Can't you think about it in the long run?
从长计议不行吗
No.
我不
Can you have a little ambition?
你有点出息行不行
Qing
小晴
Where is your dignity?
尊严呢
What's the use of dignity?
要尊严有什么用啊
Don't stop me.
别拦着我
Mengyuan, Mengyuan
梦圆 梦圆
You're at least a sportsman.
你好歹也是个运动达人
I don't want to stay here.
我不要待在这儿了
I want to go home.
我要回家
No, no.
不要 不要
You are at least good at fitness.
你好歹也是个健身达人
You have to have dignity.
你得有尊严啊
What's the point of dignity?
尊严有什么用啊
I can't.
不行了
No, no.
不要 不要
I want to go home.
我要回家
Taxi, wait for me.
师傅等等我
Taxi.
师傅
Qing
小晴
Don't be too extreme.
你别太极端了
In fact
其实啊八百米
there are many people
跑不及格的人
who failed the 800-meter-run.
大有人在
However
但是呢
according to my experience in these three years
根据我这三年的经验
as long as you go on the field
只要你上场
even if you walk to the end
哪怕最后走到底
you will have scores.
都是会有分数的
No, I definitely can't.
不行 我肯定不行
Ask your own heart
你问问你自己的内心
what you really want.
你到底想要什么
Just go for it.
想要什么就去做
Whatever the way
不管用什么方式
you have to say it.
你要说出来
If you say it
你说出来
even if
就算有百分之
there is a 99% chance
九十九的可能
of being rejected
被拒绝
you still have
但你还有
a 1% chance
百分之一的可能
of being accepted.
被接受啊
But if you do not say
但是你不说
the possibility will always be zero.
可能性就永远都是零
I'm not going.
我不去
If it takes me ten minutes to walk the 800 meters
我花十分钟走完八百米
I might as well not walk.
我还不如不走呢
The whole school will laugh at me.
全校同学都会笑话我
I will not walk.
我不走
Qing
小晴
No one wants to be the last.
没有人想当最后一名
Even no one
甚至都没有人
wants to be the second.
想当第二名
But think about it
但你想想
who can
什么人可能是
do the best of everything?
什么都做到最好
Your own idea matters.
关键是你自己的想法
Do you care more about
你是比较在意那些
what those unacquainted
平时只是点头之交
onlookers think
那些围观群众的想法
or do you value us more?
还是更看重我们
But it's too embarrassing to be rejected.
可是被拒绝也太丢人了
What's wrong with being embarrassed?
丢人怎么了
What will you lose for that?
丢人能少块肉吗
If you don't do something embarrassing
你不做点尴尬的事
can you still call it youth?
你还能叫青春吗
If you don't do something stupid now
你现在不做点蠢事
will you do it when you are forty?
你等你四十岁再做啊
If you leave
你要是走了
who will accompany us to the milk tea store?
谁陪我们打卡奶茶店
There will be no group purchase price for cosmetics.
化妆品也不能团购价了
The most important thing is
最重要的是
who will chat with you
谁陪你半夜聊到
in the middle of the night?
天南海北呀
Mengyuan
梦圆
If you really take Jing Wen
你如果真的真的拿静雯
as the girl
当做你可以为之
you can give everything for
付出一切的女孩
I think face
我觉得面子
is not at all
根本就不是
what you need to consider.
你需要考虑的问题
Nan Bei
南北呀
Are you persuading yourself
你这是在劝你自己呢
or Mengyuan?
还是劝梦圆呢